The specially administrated zone of Nippon...
行政特区日本
There are some unpleasant rumors now
spreading about Princess Euphemia over this.
ユーフェミア皇女殿下には
良からぬ噂もありますが…
You're referring to the Kamine Island matter, right?
That's where she made contact with Zero.
神根島の件だろ？
ゼロと接触していたと…
I think there may be some
connection with the top level.
まさか トップレベルで
繋がっているのでは？
There's none. The viceroy wasn't the
only one asking what was going on.
それは ない
問いただしたのは総督だけではないのだ
In any case, our connections
with them must be...
いずれにしろ あそことの関係は…
Right, we'll have to
sever ties at once.
ああ　断ち切るべきだろう
Too late.
遅すぎましたな
あ！
お… ああ！
All the evidence has
been gathered, Vice-Minister.
証拠は全て揃いましたよ 事務次官
The profit-sharing bribes from the N.A.C.
ＮＡＣからの利益供与
Gen. Darlton, I appreciate this.
With this...
ダールトン将軍 感謝します
これで…
With this, we can finally sweep away the
parasites who were sucking Prince Clovis dry.
これで やっとクロヴィス殿下を
食い物にしてきた輩を掃除できます
ふふふ
More rats than
expected are confused...
ユーフェミア皇女殿下の特区構想に
by Princess Euphemia's proposed
special zone, aren't they?
慌てたネズミは
予想以上に多かったですな
Over twenty thousand people have
applied to join the Nippon special zone.
特区 日本への申請は
20万人を超えました
The way things look,
that number's just going to grow.
この様子だと まだまだ増えますね
Thanks to you.
あなたの おかげです
は？
Because of what you represent
to the Japanese people,
あなたという
日本人の代表がいるからこそ
everyone believes in
what we're doing here.
皆さんはここを信じられるんですね
No... It must be because of the
proclamation you made, Princess.
いいえ
皇女殿下
自らの宣言があったからでしょう
I'm thankful for this.
Truly thankful.
感謝しています　本当に…
As I am to you.
私の方こそ…
I hope you'll help me with
everything that's still to come.
これからも
いろいろと助けて下さいね
Yes, Your...
イエス ユア…
Please.
もう…
あ… はい
Yes.
うふ
Yumemiteta yume
The dream that I dreamed
夢見てた夢
Hatenai tooku
Endless and distant
果て無き遠く
Kawaita hibi no sorairo, te no naka
The sky-blue of dry days, in my hands
乾いた日々の 空色・手の中
Toukankaku oto no naka de
In the space between each tick of the clock
等間隔 音の中で試行錯誤
Shikousakugo
Trial and error
Jikan kankaku no nai kuukan
A space without distance or time
時間・間隔の無い空間
Toushindai oto wo tatete
Making a life-sized sound
等身大 音をたてて
Boku no kao tsukutte yuku
It defines my face
僕の顔　造って行く
Kirei ni katahou dake
Cleanly, but only one side
キレイに　片方だけ
Kono te ni ochita
This rotting apple...
この手に落ちた
Kusarikake no ringo
That's fallen into my hand
腐りかけのリンゴ
Kagami ni utsuru
Reflecting in the mirror
鏡に映る　僕らの裏側まで
Bokura no uragawa made
Even showing our other side
Toukankaku oto no naka de
In the space between each tick of the clock
遠感覚 人の中で試行錯誤
Shikousakugo
Trial and error
Jikan kankaku no nai kuukan
A space without distance or time
時間・感覚の無い空間
Toushindai tsume wo tatete
With life-sized claws bared
頭身台 爪をたてて
Boku no kao wo kezutte yuku
I shave my face
僕の顔　削って行く
Kirei ni katahou dake
Cleanly, but only one side
キレイに　片方だけ
Toukankaku
A distant sensation
－遠感覚
Toukankaku
A distant sensation
BLOODSTAINED EUPHY
ブリタニア初の試みとなる
この行政特区日本は
The specially administrated zone of Nippon,
the first attempt its type in Britannia,
ユーフェミア皇女殿下
自らの ご発案との事で
was personally proposed by Her
Highness Princess Euphemia.
その斬新な発想は
It cannot be dismissed
that this novel idea...
殿下が先日まで学生であった事と
無関係では ないようです
is connected to the princess
being a student a short while ago.
ユーフェミア様が言う事なんだから
If Princess Euphemia says it's a
good idea, then even I have to...
あたしも…
明日の式典は
全世界に中継される予定です
大したものだね ユフィは
Euphy really is quite amazing, isn't she?
これでエリア11のテロ組織は
民衆の支持を失い瓦解する
Now the terror groups in Area 11 will
lose their popular support and fall apart.
治安も安定するよ
Public order will be stabilized.
個人的には反対です
I personally oppose this.
でも 君だって分かっているからこそ
ダールトンを補佐につけたんだろ？
But, since you understand the situation,
you've sent Darlton to advise her, correct?
おおやけの政策を軌道に乗せる
総督として当然の処置です
To ensure public policy stays on track.
It's an obvious measure
for a viceroy to take.
ふむ
Hmm...
ユフィの今後を受け入れたのも
おおやけの立場としてかな？
Did you accept Euphy's future from the
standpoint of a public official as well?
あ…
特区日本　悪い話ではない
The Nippon special zone...
It doesn't sound that bad.
与えられた日本に
果たして価値がありましょうか？
Will the Japan they hand
over have any value?
今回の譲歩を引き出したのは
我らの抵抗活動の成果だ
This concession came as a
result of our resistance activities.
恥じる事はない
There's no shame in it.
桐原候
Master Kirihara!
あなたは サクラダイト採掘に絡んで
Did I hear correctly that you
were promised a position...
特区での地位を約束されていると
聞きましたが？
in the special zone involving
the Sakuradite mining rights?
勘ぐるではない　式典参加の要請だけ
Nothing to be suspicious of.
It's just a request to
participate in the ceremony.
うまい言い抜けを
Clever excuse...
主ら…
How dare you...
ゼロは？
And Zero?
What about the Black Knights?
黒の騎士団は どうなりましょう？
The situation's serious!
It's not just supporters.
事態は深刻だ　支持者だけではない
団員の中からも
特区に参加する人間が出てきている
Some of our own members have
applied to the special zone!
黒の騎士団と違って
特区日本にはリスクがありませんしね
Unlike the Black Knights, there's no
risk in joining the Nippon special zone.
それに 由緒正しいお姫様と
正体不明の仮面の男じゃ
Besides, when you compare the pedigreed
princess and the unknown masked man,
it's clear which one
is more appealing.
どう見ても あっちの方が よさげだし
キョウトも向こうに協力するって話だ
Word is that Kyoto is
cooperating with them, too.
なんだよ そりゃ！
What's up with that?!
平等って言われちゃあな
Probably 'cuz they're
offering equality.
平等なんて
口だけで信用できないって！
Equality my ass!
We can't just take their word for it!
賛成
I agree.
あ…
でも今は 早急に対応を決めないと
But unless we decide how
to respond to this quickly...
特区に参加したいって？
You want to apply to the special zone?
あそこなら
There it won't matter who's
Britannian and who's an Eleven.
ブリタニアとか イレヴンという
縛りは関係ないし
なあ
Listen, if it works like
Euphemia's proposal,
ユーフェミアの提案通り
黒の騎士団ごと参加する訳には
いかないかな？
then it wouldn't be wrong for the
Black Knights to support it, right?
だから ブリタニアの約束は
Like she said,
can we trust their promises?
ゼロが言っている事と
特区に参加する事は矛盾しないだろ？
Supporting the special zone doesn't
contradict what Zero's said, does it?
でも それは…
But, that's...
まず平和という名目で
武装を解除させられるな
First off, they'll force us to disarm.
そりゃ困ったわぁ
That is a problem, isn't it?
我々は体制に取り込まれ
独立は失われる
And we'll get swallowed up in their
regime and lose our independence.
しかし 参加しなければ
自由と平等の敵となる
On the other hand, if we don't support it,
we become the enemies of freedom and equality.
だったら まず参加して…
Then first we have to support it!
なんの保証もなくですか？
Without any guarantees?
でも 無視はできない！
But we can't ignore it, either!
悪いな　寄り道してもらって
Sorry about having you drop me off like this.
買い出しに付き合ってもらったし
Well, you helped me stock up on food and
I heard you were meeting up with Shirley.
シャーリーと
待ち合わせって聞いたらさ
どうせ向こうも買い出しだろ
She's probably stocking up on food, too.
行政特区が始まるからって
騒ぎすぎなんだよ
Everyone's getting panicky
about this special zone starting.
はいはい
Right, right. Anyway, you'd better
make up with Shirley, soon.
それより 早くシャーリーと
仲直りしてくんないと
何が行政特区だ！
I don't care about your "special zone!"
I don't care about "support!"
何が援助だ！
署名などするものか！
I'd sooner die than sign that!
あーらら 貴族さんかしら？
Oh, dear. It's Mr. Nobleman.
もう平等になった気か？
You think you're equal, now?!
下の者はおとなしく
上に従っておればいいのだ！
The lower classes should just obey
their betters without any back talk!
確かに　それが副総督の博愛
その正体だ
There it is. That's the true nature of
the sub-viceroy's "benevolence."
なんだ お前は？
What do you want?
そうやって上から見下ろすのは
さぞや いい気分だろうな
Looking down from above.
It feels good, doesn't it?
そこまでだ 学生　下がってろ
Hold it, student. Back off.
君こそ早く うちに帰りたまえ
You should be the one who has to go home
ん…
うん そうだな
Yeah, you're right.
I'll be leaving now.
では 私はこれで
は？
お おい… 何を言っとる
Hey, what did you say?
Come back at once!
戻らんか こら！
どうした？　貴族様
What's wrong, Mr. Nobleman?
借り物の力を自らの能力と勘違いする
Don't mistake borrowed power for your own ability!
貴様のようなクズは人知れず死んで…
Garbage like you should just die where no one can...
うっ…
Come on, let's break this up.
まあまあ この辺にしとこって
おっさんも一言ぐらい謝ったら？
Why don't you apologize too, Mister?
ぶ 無礼者！　わしは…
Insolent whelp! Why should I?!
失せろ！
Get lost!
うっ…
ふん！
あ… ありがとうございます
Um... Thank you very much.
あ… いや
Oh, it was nothing.
イレヴンを助けた　ゼロなのに
He saved that Eleven,
even though he's Zero!
いえ… ゼロだから？
Or... Because he's Zero?
だったら… どうして
ユーフェミア様と一緒に？
But then, why was he talking
with Princess Euphemia?
ダメ… 深入りしたら危ないかも
Stop it... If I dig too deep,
it'll be dangerous.
ＮＡＣ いや…
The N.A.C.... Or rather, Kyoto,
as it's known among the terrorists.
テロリストの間では
キョウトという名称らしい
明日の式典を解散してフジを出る
Tomorrow, after the ceremony, why don't
you break up your group and leave Mt. Fuji?
無血開城するならば
司法取引の話をしてもよい
If they surrender peacefully,
we can talk about a legal deal.
んん？
当然 黒の騎士団への援助は終わりだ
Of course, your support
to the Black Knights will end.
明日 ゼロが来る来ないに関わらず
これであの男の敗北は確定した
Whether Zero comes or not
tomorrow doesn't matter.
With this, that man's defeat is assured.
ふ…
ん？
ただいま
I'm home.
Welcome home, big brother.
Where's Shirley?
お帰りなさい お兄様
シャーリーさんは？
Sorry, she never showed up.
I couldn't contact her, either.
いや 結局来なかったんだよ
連絡も取れないし
ちょっとした仕返しかも
More of her getting back at you, huh?
You seem sort of cold towards her lately.
最近冷たかったみたい ですから
そうかな？　反省するよ
You think so? I'll consider that.
ああ 咲世子さん
お茶を入れてくれないか？
Oh, Sayoko, could you bring
us some tea, please?
はい　かしこまりました
Yes, as you wish.
ん…
何か心配事でも あるんですか？
Are you worried about something?
え？
ユフィ姉様の事？
Is it about Euphy?
また会いたいなんて
わがままは 言いません
I won't be selfish and say
I want to see her again.
お兄様とユフィ姉様に
迷惑がかかりますもの
It would just cause trouble for you and Euphy.
ユフィの事好きかい？
You like Euphy, don't you?
ええ　お兄様だって 好きでしょ？
Yes, the same way you like her.
ああ
Yeah... I did like her.
好きだったよ
こちら 行政特区日本
開設記念式典会場です
This is the stadium for the inaugural ceremony
for the specially administrated zone of Nippon.
会場内は既に たくさんのイレヴン…
いえ 日本人で埋め尽くされています
The stadium is already stuffed full with Elevens...
Sorry, I mean with Japanese.
会場の外にも入場できなかった
大勢の日本人が集まっています
Many Japanese who could not
get inside are gathered outside.
レズリーさん
ゼロは姿を現すのでしょうか？
Lesley, do you think
Zero will show up here?
いえ…
現時点までなんの連絡もないようです
No, he's apparently made
no contact at this point in time.
CHINESE FEDERATION
EXECUTIVE CONFERENCE CHAMBER
ふふふふ
来るものか　ゼロなど
現れるはずがない
我々が入手した
彼らのデータが真実ならな
E.U. CENTRAL COUNCIL CHAMBER
ユーフェミア様　時間です
Princess Euphemia, it's time.
はい
Right.
んん…
おお…
あ…
ゼロ…
Zero.
ゼロだ！
It's Zero!
ゼロが現れたぞ！
Zero's appeared!
来てくれたのですね
He came after all!
負けを認めたか
You accept that you've lost?
どういう つもりだ？
What are you planning?!
お前の正体は わしが墓まで
持っていくつもり だったものを
I thought I would have to carry
your identity with me to the grave!
ゼロがブリタニアの皇子だと知れたら
全てが終わる
If it becomes known that Zero is
a Britannian prince, it's all over!
ブリタニア人による茶番だと誤解される
They'll mistake this for a farce
planned by the Britannians!
この行政特区すら終わってしまうぞ
It'll be the end of this specially administrated zone!
相手はゼロだ　不審な動きをした場合は
即座に射殺せよ
Your target is Zero. If he makes any
suspicious moves, kill him at once!
イエス マイ・ロード
Yes, My Lord!
ようこそ ゼロ！
Welcome, Zero! Welcome to the
specially administrated zone of Nippon!
行政特区日本へ
ユーフェミア・リ・ブリタニア
Euphemia li Britannia!
I sincerely wish to speak with you!
折り入って お話ししたい事があります
わたくしと？
With me?
はい　あなたと２人きりで
Yes! With you alone!
大変な事になりました
Something major has happened,
ladies and gentlemen!
あのゼロが堂々と姿を現しました
Zero has boldly appeared!
今 ユーフェミア殿下の指示で
Ｇ－１へと向かいます
Under Princess Euphemia's directions,
he is moving toward G1.
やっぱり
私達も行くべき だったのでは？
I knew we should have gone there.
仕方ないでしょ？
What choice did we have?
ランスロットが待ち構えていたら
ゼロが来ないかもって
Everyone said that if Lancelot was
there waiting, Zero wouldn't show.
みんな言うんだからさ
特に問題はないようです
There doesn't seem to be
any obvious problem.
では こちらへ
Then this way, please.
ユーフェミア様
Princess Euphemia, it's dangerous
to be alone with this man!
やはり この男と２人っきりに
なるのは危険です
せめて 自分だけでも…
At least let me come with you!
大丈夫です　私を信じて下さい
It's all right.
Please, just trust me.
あ…
なあ
C'mon, how long are we
supposed to hang around here?
俺達いつまで
ここにいりゃあ良いんだよ？
ゼロがここで待てって言ったのに
信じられないの？
Wasn't having Zero tell us to
wait here enough for you?
だってよぉ
Yeah, but...
全てはブリタニアの真意を
確かめてからだ
Everything starts after we confirm
the Britannian's real intentions.
副指令
Deputy-commander?
はっ はい
Hm? Yes?
その真意が分かっているからこそ
全軍を四方に伏せてあるのでは？
Because he knows
what their intentions are,
he's told all of us to hide and stand
by at all four corners, hasn't he?
断定は危険です
It's dangerous
to draw conclusions.
ディートハルトやラクシャータまで
待機させた
He's even having Diethard
and Rakshata standing by.
ゼロは 恐らくユーフェミアを…
I think he may be
planning to kill Euphemia...
用心深いのね
You're taking a lot of care, aren't you?
Even though the cameras are off.
カメラならオフにしてあるのに…
ずっと隠れてきたからな
どこかの帝国のせいで
Because I've been in hiding for a long time.
The fault of a certain empire, I'm afraid.
セラミックと竹を使用したニードルガン
これは検知器では見つからない
This is needle gun,
made from ceramic and bamboo.
It can't be picked up on a detector.
ルルーシュ　あなた撃たないでしょ？
Lelouch...
You wouldn't shoot me, would you?
そう 俺は撃たない
No, I wouldn't.
撃つのは君だよ　ユフィ
You'll be doing the shooting, Euphy.
え？
大丈夫かな？
ゼロと２人きりなんて…
Is this really all right,
leaving her alone with Zero?
でも ご命令じゃあ
But she ordered us!
緊急時のコールスイッチは
渡してあるから
There's an emergency call button she can press.
あっ…
あ…
えっ？
ん？
どうしました？
What's wrong?
なぜ ゼロなんかと一緒に…
What are you doing with Zero?!
見えているようだな
It looks like he can see me.
間接接触と神根島の件が
きっかけになったか…
Is it because of our indirect contact
and what happened at Kamine Island?
それとも あいつが？
Or is it because he?
But, if that's the case, then...
だとしたら…
CODE GEASS
Lelouch of the Rebellion
This ceremony is being
broadcast worldwide.
この式典は世界中に中継されている
And the world's going to see you,
a Britannian princess, shoot Zero.
そこでブリタニアの皇女である君が
ゼロを撃つ
どうなると思う？
What do you think will happen then?
暴動になるんじゃないかしら？
Violence would break out, I imagine.
ああ
Right.
騙し撃ちされたとなれば
ゼロは殉教者となり
Zero will become a martyr,
tricked into a deathtrap,
君の信望は地に落ちる
and your popularity will crash to the Earth.
何 ふざけてるんですか？
What kind of nonsense are you saying?
Help me rebuild Japan...
私と一緒に日本を…
上から一方的に押し付けるのなら
クロヴィスと同じだな
If you arbitrarily push it upon us from on
high, you're being just as bad as Clovis was!
え？
もう全ての条件はクリアされた
All conditions for this
situation have been cleared.
ゼロは生死をさまよい
奇跡の復活を遂げ 称えられる
After hovering near death, Zero will be cheered
when he makes a miraculous recovery.
人は理屈ではなく
奇跡に弱いものなんだよ
People don't care about reason.
But they can't resist a good miracle.
さあ 受け取りたまえ
Now, take the gun.
はあ？
メシアは１人でなければ ならない
君が偽者だと分かれば民衆は…
There can be only one messiah.
Once they see you're a false one, the people will...
うっ！
や やっぱり…
I... I thought so!
１つだけ答えろ　お前は…
Just tell me one thing! Are you...
うっ！
ぐううっ…
あ…
まさか… もう…
No... He's reached that point?!
おい どうした？
Hey! What's wrong?!
あ…
あ あ…
うっ…
あ… ああ…
枢木少佐！
Maj. Kururugi!
貴様！
Why, you! What have you done?!
何をした！
くっ
うわあああ！
ルルーシュ！
Lelouch!
やめろ！
Stop it! Stop giving me your pity!
これ以上 俺を哀れむな！
施しは受けない！
I won't take your charity!
I have to try and achieve this on my own!
俺は 自分の力で手に入れてみせる！
その為にも汚れてもらうぞ！
And for that, I'll stain your hands
with blood, Euphemia li Britannia!
ユーフェミア・リ・ブリタニア！
その名は返上しました！
I've given up that name!
あっ…
いずれ本国から発表があると思いますが
皇位継承権を返上しました
There'll probably be an announcement
from the homeland soon,
but I've given up my claim to the throne!
なぜ？
Why? Not because you accepted Zero, is it?
まさかゼロを受け入れたから？
私のわがままを
聞いてもらうのですから
A price had to be paid for doing
something this selfish, right?
それなりの対価は必要でしょ？
あ…
随分と簡単に捨てられるんだな 君は…
It's easy for you to give it up, isn't it?
I suppose you did it for my sake.
俺の為だとでも言うのか？
うふ
相変わらず自信家ね
You're as conceited as ever, I see.
I did it for Nunnally!
ナナリーの為よ
う…
あの子 言ったの
She told me herself. "As long as I can be
with my brother, I don't need anything else."
“お兄様と一緒にいられれば
他に何もいらない”って
そんな事で？
And that's why you?!
そんな事で決心がついちゃったの
And that's what made up my mind.
私にとって 本当に大事なものは
なんだろうって
It made me consider what
was truly important to me.
だからルルーシュ？
So do you see, Lelouch? I'm not giving
up anything that's truly important to me.
私は 本当の本当に大切なものは
１つも捨てていないわ
安心して あなた達の事は誰にも…
And don't worry!
I won't tell anyone about you!
ふん
ふはははは
コーネリアは？
And Cornelia?
別に会えなくなる訳じゃあ
It's not like we'll never
see each other again.
バカだよ 君は
You're a fool. An amazing fool.
大バカだ
そりゃあゲームでも勉強でも
I may not have ever been able to beat
you at games or studies, Lelouch, but...
ルルーシュに勝った事は
一度もありませんけど
しかし 無茶なやり方なのに
結局 全てを手に入れてしまう
But in your own rash way,
you ended up winning it all.
考えてみれば 君はいつも
副総督や 皇女殿下である前に
When I think about it, more than
being the sub-viceroy or a princess,
ただのユフィだったな
you were always just plain little Euphy.
ただのユフィなら一緒にやってくれる？
Then will you do this
with plain little Euphy?
ん…
君は
You... You are the worst
enemy I ever faced.
俺にとって最悪の敵だったよ
ふっ
君の勝ちだ
You win.
え？
この行政特区を生かす形で策を練ろう
Let's figure out a better use
for this special zone of yours.
あっ！
ああ 部下になる訳じゃないからな？
Oh, but I won't act as your
subordinate, all right?
ええ でも私って信用ないのね
Right! Still, you don't have
much faith in me, do you?
ん？
脅されたからって
私がルルーシュを撃つと思ったの？
Did you really think you could get me
to shoot you just by threatening me?
ああ 違うんだよ
Oh, no, that's not it.
俺が本気で命令したら
誰だって逆らえないんだ
If I really order someone to do
something, no one can resist.
俺を撃て　スザクを解任しろ
To shoot me, to dismiss Suzaku, any order at all.
どんな命令でもな
もう 変な冗談ばっかり
Oh, you're just being silly now.
本当だよ
I'm serious! For example, if told you "Kill all the
Japanese," it wouldn't matter how you felt about it...
例えば 日本人を殺せって言ったら
君の意思とは関係なく…
はっ！
嫌… 私が…
No... Please, I don't... No!
嫌っ…
あっ…
殺したくない！
I don't want to kill them!
嫌っ…
No!
うっ… ううう…
なっ…
まさか！
Did I?!
そうね　日本人は殺さなきゃ
You're right.
I have to kill the Japanese.
なっ…
俺もマオと同じように
ギアスのオン オフができない…
I've become like Mao!
I can't control my Geass now!
くっ 今の命令は忘れろ！
Forget the order
I just gave you! Euphy!
ユフィ！
あっ…
待ってくれ！　ユフィ！
Euphy, wait!
ああ
Right, I've completed the talks
with the Chinese Federation,
中華連邦との話はついたから
今日中に本国に戻るよ
so I'll be returning
to the homeland today.
では実験適合生体はまだこちらに？
Then we should keep the
experimental adapted organism here?
うん　知能は？
Right. How's his intelligence look?
エリア11では限界がありまして
There's only so much
we can do here in Area 11.
そうか　ローゼンバーグ研究所に
話をしてみよう
I see. We should ask the
Rosenberg Institute about that.
連絡がついたら あの実験機とセットで
送ってもらえるかな？
Can you send him and the test unit over
there after I make arrangements there?
分かりました
Understood, Your Highness.
That just leaves the Kamine Island ruins...
あと神根島の遺跡ですが…
エリア11の治安が安定してからだよ
その為の行政特区
It'll have to wait till the security
situation in Area 11 has stabilized.
We have the specially
administrated zone to thank for that.
感謝しないとね
ユーフェミアのおかげで
Thanks to Euphemia, it looks like
everything's going to work out perfectly.
全てうまく いきそうだから
副総督！　ゼロは？
Sub-viceroy, where's Zero?!
日本人を名乗る皆さん
All of you who call yourselves Japanese...
はぁ？
お願いがあります
I have a favor to ask!
Could you all die, please?
死んでいただけないでしょうか？
えっ？
今 なんて言った？
What did she just say?
嘘だろ？
No way...
冗談…
It's a joke, right?
くっ スザク！
Suzaku!
気絶しているだけか
He's just unconscious.
But why?!
しかし なぜ？
えーっと
Umm...
あ！
自殺して欲しかったんですけど
ダメですか？
I was hoping you'd commit suicide,
but you can't, can you?
じゃあ 兵士の方々
皆殺しにして下さい
Well then, soldiers, please kill them all.
Wipe them out!
虐殺です！
なっ！
本気か？
She's serious?!
マイクとカメラを切れ！
Cut the mics and cameras!
やめろ！　ユフィ！
Euphy, no!
止まれ！
Halt!
ほっとけ！
Out of my way!
Damn terrorist!
テロリストが！
どくんだ！
Stand aside!
うっ…
わああああ！
さあ！　兵士の皆さんも早く！
Go on, soldiers! Hurry!
ユーフェミア様！
Princess Euphemia!
What's come over you?!
いったい どうなさったのですか？
おやめください こんな事は…
Stop this, please! This is...
ぐっ…　おお…
将軍！
General!
うっ…
ごめんなさい
Forgive me, but I have
to kill all the Japanese.
でも日本人は皆殺しにしないと
いけないの
さあ！
Now then, all Britannians!
ブリタニアの皆さん
あ…
は！
Kill the Elevens!
All troops, exterminate the Elevens!
イレヴンを殺せ
全軍 イレヴンを殲滅せよ
１人も逃がすな
Don't let one escape!
Kill them all!
やめろ！　何する！
Stop it! What are you doing?!
自分はブリタニア軍 名誉騎士候
枢木スザクだ！
This is Suzaku Kururugi,
Knight of Honor of the Britannian Forces!
今すぐ戦闘をやめろ！
Cease fire at once!
日本人は全て抹殺しろとの命令だ
We were ordered to kill all the Japanese here.
Princess Euphemia ordered it personally.
ユーフェミア様 直々のな
何？　ユーフェミア様が？
What? Princess Euphemia did?
Don't be ridiculous!
バカを言うな！
お前も日本人だったな
You're Japanese too, aren't you?
はっ…
なっ… なんだ？
What's happening?!
中で なんかあったの？
What happened in there?!
祝砲？　そんな訳ないだろ
Gun fire?
It can't be. What does the TV say?
テレビは？　中継が切れてて…
They cut the feed!
やめろ！　ユフィ！
EUPHY, STOP!!!
これを…
This... My Geass did this?!
俺のギアスが…
ゼ… ゼロ…
Z- Zero...
うっ
私達を…
Help us... Japan's... savior...
日本…
救世主…
やめろ…
Stop it...
私は救世主じゃ…
I'm not your savior.
I'm not your messiah!
メシアなんかじゃ ないんだ…
希望…
You're... You're our only... hope...
あなた だけ…
やめろ…
Stop...
俺に…
Don't... Don't force me...
俺に押し付けるな…
罪を償えと？
I have to atone for this sin?
Bear this cross, too?!
背負い込めというのか？
俺が…
ゼロ…
Zero... What did you do
to Princess Euphemia?!
くっ…  貴様…
ユーフェミア様に… 何をした？
アンドレアス・ダールトン
Andreas Darlton...
コーネリアの側近中の側近だったのに
The closest of Cornelia's close advisors.
何？　会場で何が起こったの？
What?! What's happening in the stadium?!
今 確かめてるよ！
We're figuring that out!
えー ただいま… 会場との…
継が… うまくいっており…
We're getting a feed
from the stadium now.
なぜ切り替わらない？
Why can't you cut this off?!
これ どこかから
ハッキングされてますよ
Someone's hacking this
in from somewhere!
止めろ！
世界中に流れているんだぞ！
Stop it!
It's going live to the entire world!
そろそろ放送が中断される
They'll cut the broadcast soon.
Let's upload the data to the Net.
ネットにデータをアップしろ
だってさ
You heard him!
はい
Right.
参謀！
C.C.が総司令と合流したそうです
Sir! C.C. has made contact
with the supreme commander!
よおし！　これで問題はなくなった
Good!
That's the last problem, cleared.
どうやってこの状況を
作ったのかは分かりませんが
I don't know how
you arranged this situation,
計画以上の策略ですよ ゼロ
but this scheme is beyond
what we planned, Zero.
うっ… ぐおっ…
くっ！
驚いたぞ　ここまでするとは
I'm shocked.
I didn't think you'd go this far.
俺じゃない
It wasn't me.
何？　ああっ
What?
俺はギアスをかけていない
I didn't use my Geass.
いや かけたつもりは なかった
Or rather, I didn't mean to use it!
そうか やはり さっきのは…
I see.
Then, what I felt before was...
分かっていて俺は契約した
Even knowing the risks,
I made my contract with you.
これがヤバい力だという事くらい…
You told me how dangerous
this power was. And yet!
なのに！
わははははは！
あやつよ！　やりおったか！
He did it! He really did it!
あっ…
Wh- What is this?!
なんだ これは…
うあああん
お待ち下さい！　コーネリア様！
Princess Cornelia, wait!
ついて来られる者だけ来ればよい！
Don't follow me
unless you're coming along!
ユフィ！
Euphy!
見つかりましたか？
どこにいるのか！
Have you found her?!
Where is she?!
分からないのよ
ダールトン将軍とも連絡が取れないし
I don't know!
We can't contact Gen. Darlton, either!
何か おかしい
Something's wrong.
This isn't like Euphemia at all.
今までのユーフェミアと違いすぎます
交渉の余地があれば良いが
桐原とも繋がらんし
I wish there was room to negotiate with this,
but we can't be connected with Kirihara now!
うん… ひとまず我らだけでも
Hm, yes. For now,
we need to save ourselves.
さようですな　土産は…
Indeed. Is the "souvenir" ready?
情けない
How pathetic...
ん？
とどのつまりは我が身大事か
In the end, we value
ourselves above others.
皇よ 口が過ぎますぞ
You shouldn't say that,
Lady Sumeragi.
日本の為にも 我らが残らねば
We need to stay alive
for Japan's sake, as well.
我らだけ残って どうするのですか？
And what's the point if
we're the only ones left?!
控えい！　神楽耶！
家の格だけのおなごは！
Watch your tongue, Kaguya!
You only have your family's name backing you!
今動かずして！
なんの為のキョウトか！
If we don't act now,
what's the point of Kyoto's existence?!
ユフィが虐殺命令なんて
出すはずがない！
I can't believe Euphy would order
all those people to be exterminated!
なんとしても捜し出す！
I have to find her, somehow!
ユフィを！
あっ…
おい 会場の外に
ブリタニア軍が出てきたぞ
Hey! The Britannian forces have left the stadium!
ああ　こうなったらユーフェミアを
最大限利用するしかない
Right.
In this case, our only option is to
exploit Euphemia to the utmost.
それが… せめてもの…
It's the least we can do!
んん…
あ！
ゼロに通告する！
Attention, Zero! Return that unit!
That machine is the property of our military...
その機体を明け渡せ！
その機体は我が軍の…
黒の騎士団 総員に告げる！
This is an order to all Black Knights!
ユーフェミアは敵となった！
Euphemia has become our enemy!
行政特区日本は 我々をおびき出す
卑劣な罠だったのだ！
The specially administrated zone of
Nippon is a cowardly trap to lure us in!
自在戦闘装甲騎部隊は
式典会場に突入せよ！
Armored autonomous battle knight units,
break into the ceremony grounds!
ブリタニア軍を壊滅し
日本人を救い出すのだ！
Wipe out all Britannian forces!
Save the Japanese!
急げ！
Hurry!
絶対 絶対にユフィを…
I have to! I have to find Euphy!
見つけ出して 殺せ！
Find her and kill her!
モザイクカケラ ひとつひとつ
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
Hitotsu hitotsu tsunagiawasete
Coming together one by one
繋ぎ合わせて描いてゆく
Egaiteyuku
To form the picture
あなたがくれた 出逢いと別れも
Anata ga kureta deai to wakare mo
The meetings and partings I've had with you
こんなはずじゃない そう思って眠り
Konna hazu ja nai
"It can't be," I think
Sou omotte nemuri
As I go to sleep
目覚めればいつもの 変わらない空回り
Mezamereba itsumo no
When I awaken, just as always
Kawaranai karamawari
I'm left going nowhere
意味もなく繰り返し
Imi mo naku kurikaeshi
Pointlessly repeating the pattern
モザイクカケラ 鮮やかに映す
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
Azayaka ni utsusu
Clearly showing
過去の嘘も過ちも
Kako no uso mo ayamachi mo
The lies and mistakes of the past
消してしまいたいと想えば想うほど
Keshiteshimaitai to omoeba omou hodo
As much as I'd like to erase them
振り返れば
Furikaereba soko ni aru
When I look back, I see...
そこにあるスタートライン
Start line mada susun ja inai
I still haven't moved past that start line
未だ進んじゃいない
もう一度夢を拾い集めてみよう
Mou ichido yume wo
So let's try regathering
Hiroiatsumete miyou
the pieces of our dream
モザイクカケラ ひとつひとつ
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
Hitotsu hitotsu tsunagiawasete
Coming together one by one
繋ぎ合わせて描いてゆく
Egaiteyuku
To form the picture
あなたがくれた 出逢いと別れも
Anata ga kureta deai to wakare mo
The meetings and partings I've had with you
誰が作り出した？　この状況を
Who was it that created this situation?
誰の罪だ？　この惨劇は
Who is it that bears
the sin for this tragedy?
誰が望んだ？　この戦いを
Who is it that desires this battle?!
誰のものなんだ？　この世界は
And who is it that
the world belongs to?
ああ 分かっている
Yes, I understand.
だが しかし… それでも俺は
But, even so... Even so, I!